#### roshanrajan1073@gmail.com

# Kumar Ravi

2C1-Kamarahar Cross Steet, Shenbakkam, Vellore-632008, Tamil Nadu.



+91 7010252993

# ABOUT ME

# Medical Billing Designation Charge (Jun 21 2016 to May 18 2018)



Skilled and experienced Charge Entry Experience has excellent data entry skills and extensive knowledge of appropriate medical codes. Is very proficient at meeting weekly accounts receivable goals and in conducting patient ticket reconciliations. Creating the weekly and monthly report and creating a template for internal process.

### Cognizant Technology Solution India Private Ltd (July 13 2018 to Current date)



I am working in creating a MS Access and Excel automation with help of both formulas and VBA. Creating Dashboard, Data Analysis, assisting with training and onboarding processes, Report Automation for weekly and monthly report, Creating a database and etc.

#### **EDUCATION**



#### **DIPLOMA**

Gedee Technical Training Institute Coimbatore- 641 081, Tamil Nadu

10th

Konavattam Higher Secondary School Konavattam Vellore – 632008 Graduated, July 2013

Marks - 62% NCVT - 79%

**10** Jun 2009 **10** Marks 44%

#### **QUALIFICATIONS**

Diploma and NCVT

#### **AFFILIATIONS**

• 10th

#### **SKILLS**

Master Diploma in Information Technology



# WORK EXPERIENCE



- Global Healthcare Billing Partners Pvt. Ltd
- Designation Junior Executive
- Jun 21 2016 to May 18 2018
- Cognizant Technology Solution India Private Ltd
- Designation Senior Process Executive Data (MIS-Executive)
- July 13 2018 to Current date

- Cognizant Technology Solution India Private Ltd
- Designation Senior Process Executive Data (MIS-Executive)
- July 13 2018 to Current date

## **COMPUTER RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Handling Software SequelMed, Practice Max and Fazzi Charge Entry
- To verify the Patient information details and Insurance Verification
- Client mail Response
- Follow up create and follow up response
- To maintain the Efficiency and Accuracy
- Invoice Process and Batch Tally
- Excel, Excel VBA,
- MA Access

# Professional Experience

- Prepared monthly performance status reports
- Prepared production report
- Prepared quality report
- Prepared production dashboard
- Prepared output validation template
- Prepared attendance dashboard
- Prepared hourly production report

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Tamil
- ઉ.∿
- English

## **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

- Music
- Cricket
- System repair

J

0

PERSONAL **DETAILS** 

Gender: Male Marital Status: Single

Birthday:

July 17,1992

Nationality: Indian

#### **Declaration**

l, Kumar Ravi	, hereby	declare t	that the i	informati	on cont	ained h	ierein i	is true	and	correct	to the	best o	f my	knowl	edge
and belief.															

, <b>Kumar Ravi</b> , hereby declare t and belief.	hat the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my $knowled_{\xi}$
Kumar Ravi	_ Vellore, Tamil Nadu July,2022